

MAHMUDIN

CONTACT

+6285798835322

🔀 mahmudin222@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmudin-295083114

https://mhn20.github.io/portfolio/

South Tangerang, Banten, Indonesia

EDUCATION

2012-2015

Bina Sarana Informatika

Diploma III Informatics & Computer Management / GPA: 3.30

ACHIEVEMENT

 Awarded the "Best Employee" award in the last company for outstanding achievements in completing several projects with optimal results.

EXPERTISE

Hard Skills:

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- ¡Front-End Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Back-End Development: Python (Flask, Django), PHP (Codelgniter, Laravel)
- · RESTful API: Swagger, Postman, Lumen
- Database Management: Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Server and Deployment: Linux, Git, Docker, Nginx, Gunicorn
- · SSO Authentication: Keycloak
- Design: Adobe Photoshop

Soft Skills:

- · Working with Teams and Individuals
- Time Management and Responsibility
- Fast Learning and Technical Communication Skills
- · Detail, Creative and Problem Solving
- · Thoroughness and Neatness

Language Skills:

- · Indonesia (Active)
- English (Passive)

SUMMARY

A professional with more than 5 years of work experience in the IT programming field. Prioritizing work ethic, thoroughness, responsibility, and consistency in completing every job. Able to handle many applications in internal private and internal government. Have the ability to work together in a team, be organized at work, be hardworking, competent, and communicate well. Dedicated and highly motivated to develop professionally.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2019-

PT. Nawastra Teknologi Nimpuna

Present Software Engineer (Fulltime)

- Design and develop financial systems following the internal needs of Puskeu Polri to support efficient financial operations.
- Perform routine maintenance and repairs on the financial system to ensure optimal performance and system reliability.
- Develop the system using web programming languages such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Jquery) to create a responsive user interface.
- Develop systems with Python, Django and Laravel frameworks to ensure the reliability and efficiency of application development.
- To support secure and structured data storage, manage and integrate the system with databases using DBMS such as Oracle, PostgreSQL, and MySQL.

Sep 2024-Oct 2024

Yotowawa Media Center

ct 2024 Programmer (Freelance)

- Designing an Indonesian, Meher, and Woirata local language translator system to support local language preservation.
- Build a text-to-speech feature that converts text to voice in real time
- Developed a multi-user interactive quiz with grading, quiz creation, timing, and sharing features.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Jquery), Codelgniter, and Python Django to optimize system functionality.
- Maintained and integrated MySQL and SQL Lite databases for secure and structured data storage.

Jul 2017-Oct 2019

NK Multimedia

Web Developer (Fulltime)

- Design and develop a user-friendly marketing or e-commerce website to support online product sales.
- · Create a website interface using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Jquery) to be responsive and easily accessible on various devices.
- Using the Codelgniter framework to ensure efficient and wellstructured website development.
- Added e-commerce features such as a shopping cart, online payment, and inventory management to support online business processes
- Manage MySQL database for secure and organized product data, transactions, and customer information storage.

Oct 2018-Mar 2019

Tempat Pelelangan Ikan Muara Angke

Programmer (Freelance)

- Developed and updated existing systems to improve functionality and operational efficiency.
- Completed phased system development in 5 terms according to the project plan and needs.

- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Jquery) programming languages to create responsive and interactive web interfaces.
- Used Codelgniter framework to ensure structured and manageable system development.
- Managing databases using MySQL to ensure secure and efficient data storage in the system.

Aug 2018-Jan 2019

Digipro

PHP Programmer (Freelance)

- Develop and enhance existing systems to meet new needs and improve performance.
- Complete each system development task in stages according to priorities and targets set.
- Develop systems using native PHP to build lightweight and efficient applications.
- Manage databases with SQL Anywhere to ensure system data's security, integrity, and availability.
- Organize and execute system development processes in a structured manner to achieve results following specified standards.

amikbsi 0129826



Akademi Manajemen Informatika & Komputer BINA SARANA INFORMATIKA

Izin Dikti Nomor: 9928/D/T/K-III/2011, tanggal 23 Desember 2011 Terakreditasi, Nomor: 394/SK/BAN-PT/Akred/Dpl-III/X/2014



This diploma is issued by virtue of the Decision of the Minister of National Education of the Republic of Indonesia Number: 184/U/2001, dated November 23, 2001.

Dengan ini menyatakan bahwa

This is to certify that.

MAHMUDIN / 12127030

Lahir di Jakarta tanggal 28 Maret 1994

Born in Jakarta on March 28, 1994

Tahun Masuk 2012

Registration Year 2012

telah menyelesaikan dengan baik dan memenuhi segala syarat

has successfully completed and fulfilled all requirements of

Program Pendidikan Diploma Tiga

Three-Year-Diploma Program in

MANAJEMEN INFORMATIKA

Informatics Management

Konsentrasi Pemrograman Web

Concentration Web Programming

ljazah ini diserahkan berdasarkan Keputusan Direktur AMIK BSI, Nomor 0150/1.02/AMIK-BSI/IX/2015

tanggal 21 September 2015

This certificate is entitled in reference to the Decree of the Director of AMIK BSI, number 0150/1.02/AMIK-BSI/IX/2015

dated September 21, 2015

Dan kepadanya dilimpahkan segala wewenang dan hak yang berhubungan dengan

And, bef the is entitled to all the rights and privileges pertaining there

ijazah yang dimilikinya, serta berhak memakai sebutan profesional Ahli Madya (A.Md)

bef she is certified and hence has a privilege of using a professional degree "Ahli Madya (AMd)"

Jakarta, 21 September 2015

Jakarta, September 21, 2015

Direktur

Director

matri

Ir. Naba Aji Notoseputro

Pembantu Direktur I Bidang Akademik
Deputy Head I For Academic Affairs

Irmawati Carolina, S.SI, M.Kom



AMIK BSI Jakarta



Kampus A: Jl. RS. Fatmawati No.24, Pondok Labu, Jakarta Selatan, Telp.(021) 7500282
Fax.(021) 7513790, e-mail: amik.jakarta@bsi.ac.id

TRANSKRIP AKADEMIK

NAMA MAHASISWA

: MAHMUDIN

NIM

: 12127030

TEMPAT/TGL LAHIR

JAKARTA, 28-03-1994

JURUSAN

MANAJEMEN INFORMATIKA

KONSENTRASI

PEMROGRAMAN WEB

JENJANG PENDIDIKAN

DIPLOMA TIGA (D. III)

TANGGAL KELULUSAN

21 SEPTEMBER 2015

NOMOR SERI

0129826 0915

| NO | MATA KULIAH | HM | AM | SKS | MUTU |
|-----------------|--|---------|--------|-----|------|
| 4 | PENDIDIKAN PANCASILA | 8 | 3 | 2 | 6 |
| 2 | BAHASA INGGRIS I | В | 3 | 2 | 6 |
| 3 | ALGORITMA & PEMROGRAMAN I | Α. | Ã | 2 | 16 |
| 4 | PENGANTAR TEKNOLOGI INFORMASI & KOMUNIKASI | C | 2 | | 6 |
| 5 | LOGIKA & ALGORITMA * | В | 9 | | 12 |
| 6 | ENTREPRENEURSHIP | C B C C | 2 | | 6 |
| 7 | DASAR AKUNTANSI & PRAKTIK | č | 2 | 2 | 8 |
| 8 | PENDIDIKAN AGAMA | B | 3 | 2 | |
| 9 | BAHASA INGGRIS II | A | 7 | 2 | 6 |
| 10 | CHARACTER BUILDING | A | 2. | - | |
| 11 | DASAR MANAJEMEN & BISNIS | 2 | 7 | 3 | 6 |
| 12 | PERANCANGAN BASIS DATA * | | 3 | 2 | 12 |
| 13 | PRAKTIKUM PERANCANGAN BASIS DATA | A | 3 | 2 | |
| 14 | STRUKTUR DATA | В | 2 | 2 | 8 |
| 15 | SISTEM INFORMASI MANAJEMEN * | | 3 | | 12 |
| 16 | SISTEM OPERASI | B | 3 | | 12 |
| 17 | STATISTIKA DESKRIPTIF | B | 2 | 3 | 6 |
| 18 | TEKNIK PEMROGRAMAN | | 3 | 2 | 5 |
| 19 | INTERAKSI MANUSIA KOMPUTER | C | 2 | 3 | 6 |
| 20 | PEMROGRAMAN VISUAL I | В | 3 | 3 | 2 |
| 21 | ANALISA & PERANCANGAN SISTEM INFORMASI * | A | 1.5 | 4 | 16 |
| 22 | ALGORITMA & PEMROGRAMAN II | A | -4 | 4 | 16 |
| 23 | PEMROGRAMAN VISUAL II | A | - 4 | 4 | 16 |
| 24 | ETIKA PROFESI TEKNOLOGI INFORMASI & KOMUNIKASI | A | 4 | 4 | 16 |
| 25 | PENGANTAR MANAJEMEN PROYEK SISTEM INFORMASI | A | 4 | 3 | 12 |
| 26 | METODE PENELITIAN | В | 3 | 2 | 6 |
| 27 | KULIAH KERJA PRAKTEK | В | 3 | 3 | 9 |
| 28 | | A | 4 | 2 | |
| 29 | PEMODELAN SISTEM BERBASIS OBJEK WEB PROGRAMMING I | В | 3 | 4 | 12 |
| 30 | | A | 4 | 4 | 16 |
| 31 | PERANCANGAN WEB | A | 4 | 4 | 16 |
| 32 | KEWARGANEGARAAN | A | 4 | 2 | 8 |
| 33 | BAHASA INDONESIA | A | 4 | 2 | 8 |
| | WEB PROGRAMMING II | A | 4 | 4 | 16 |
| 34 | E-COMMERCE | A | 4 | 3 | 12 |
| 35 | INTERNET AND MOBILE SECURITY | В | 3 | 3 | 9 |
| 36 | TUGAS AKHIR | 8 | 3 | 6 | 18 |
| UL TUGAS AKHIR: | | | JUMLAH | 115 | 380 |

SISTEM INFORMASI PENDAFTARAN SISWA BARU BERBASIS WEB PADA SMP IT INSAN MADANI 8 TANGERANG SELATAN

INDEKS PRESTASE 3:30 PREDIKAT: SANGAT MEMUASKAN

KETERANGAN:

HM Hirruf Mutu AM Angka Mutu SKS Bobot

MUTU Multi (AM*SKS)

• Mata Kullah Unggulan

JAKARTA, 21 SEPTEMBER 2015 DIREKTUR

ir. NABA AJI NOTOSEPUTRO

PEMBANTU DIREKTUR I BIDANG AKADEMIK

IRMAWATI CAROLINA, S.SI, M.Kom